能量信号变强了
Energon signal's gettin' stronger.
大概在北方五公里处
About five clicks due north.
你说什么？限速？
What do you mean, speed limit?
我这里有一档可以开到150码!
I have a gauge in here that goes to 150.
要是设计这车的人类不希望它跑那么快
If the humans who designed my vehicle form didn't want it to go that fast
那就不该给我装这个档!
they shouldn't have given me the option.
哇哦！
Whoa!
嘿 飙车少年！
Hey, Indy 500!
等咱俩完事之后
When I'm through with you
恐怕你要修的就不光是车了
you're gonna need more than a pit crew to put you back together!
来啊！
Bring it!
看看到底谁更经打 嗯？
Who's the tough guy now, huh?
哈哈哈 别紧张 大黄蜂
Hahaha. Relax, Bumblebee.
我只不过开个玩笑而已
I'm just messin' around.
找到了!
Found it.
愤怒的老司机毫不迟疑地发布了你的照片！
Old road rage didn't waste any time posting your mug shots.
等拉夫回到家后 他会把这照片擦掉的
Raf will scrub this as soon as he's back from house hunting.
你跟钛师傅是怎么学的？
Is this what you learned while serving Alpha Trion?!
我严重怀疑他能否饶恕你这种不负责任的行为!
I highly doubt that he would have condoned such irresponsible behavior.
不要解除你的伪装!
Blowing your cover is not okay.
对不起 伙计们 我知道我真的闯了大祸
Sorry, guys. I know I really messed up.
救护车和阿尔茜说的都对
While Ratchet and Arcee are correct
不过我觉得这件事我们都有责任
I believe that we are all equally responsible for this incident.
我们？
Us?
怎么可能！
How?
我们又不在场！
We weren't even there.
好吧 小蜂在
Well, Bee was.
我们最近过多地专注于解决危机
Our recent efforts have been so intensely focused on averting crises
却忽略了一些基础事项
that we have overlooked simple matters
比如 教会烟幕在这个星球上的生存之道
such as teaching Smokescreen how to best function on this planet.
我们要弥补这一过失
It is an oversight that must be corrected.
擎天柱 我很荣幸能接受您的教导
Optimus, I'm honored to train under you
我会不遗余力去弥补过失
and will do whatever it takes to make things right
为您争光
to make you proud.
也许了解人类世界的最好方法 是向人类请教
Perhaps the best way for you to learn about the human world is from a human.
再给烟幕找个搭档？
Smokescreen gets his own partner?
拜托 这里的三个人类还嫌不够多吗？
Please! Isn't having three humans here enough?
我指的是已经和我们在一起的某位
I was referring to one already among us.
啊… 没问题 擎天柱
Um... sure, Optimus.
隐蔽机器人形态 学习交通法规
Um, robots in disguise, traffic laws
不要殴打人类…
don't beat down humans...
我会让烟幕学好的
I can bring Smokescreen up to speed.
我们都经历过学习期
We've all put in curbside duty.
这是任务的一部分！
Part of the gig.
那我们上路吧 老师
Then let's go for a drive, teach.
擎天柱 恕我直言
Optimus, with all due respect
由于霸天虎发现了拉夫的住址
Agent Fowler is out relocating Raf's family
福勒探员正忙着帮拉夫搬家
because the Cons discovered where he lives.
然而烟幕自作聪明选择的汽车形态
Meanwhile, Smokescreen, in all his wisdom
车门上印着一对招摇过市的38
chooses a vehicle mode with screaming double "38S" on the doors
很容易被辨识出来
making him an easy target.
我没法假装我一点也不担心杰克的安危
I'd be lying if I said I wasn't more than concerned about Jack's safety.
但是
Nonetheless
我们的新人的确需要指导
the fact remains that our new recruit is in need of instruction.
我相信烟幕有一颗善良的火种
I believe that Smokescreen's spark is in the right place
而且他也已经懂得了必须要保护人类
and that he now understands the necessity of protecting humanity.
好 到路口了 复习一下
Okay, intersection. Let's review.
绿灯？
Light's green?
绿灯行
Green for "go".
黄灯？
And yellow?
加速！
Go faster!
喔 烟幕
Whoa, whoa! Smokescreen!
哈哈哈 只是开个玩笑
Hahahaha. Just messin' around!
哈-哈-
Ha-ha-
啊噢
Uh-oh.
怎么了？有虎子？
What is it? Cons?
只是个学校里我不想见的人
Just someone from school I'd rather not talk to.
开车！
Drive!
红灯 教练 不能走!
Red light, teach. No can do.
搞什么？
Seriously?
算了随他去吧
Just... let it go.
你没开玩笑吧？
Are you kiddin' me?
你的自尊呢？
Where's your self-respect?
我们得为自己出头！
We gotta stand up for ourselves.
我们还得遵守擎天柱的规定
We also have to follow Optimus' rule.
不光要保护人类
It's not just about protecting humans...
也不能伤害他们
you can't harm them, either.
我说过要伤害谁吗？
Who said anything about harming?
今晚我要把这个发出去！
I am so posting this tonight.
阿尔茜 阿尔茜 来看看文斯的车！
Arcee! Arcee, check out Vince's car!
那个小混混
The bully?
嘿 文斯 还想加点薯条吗？
Hey, Vince, did you want fries with that?
我来把这事捋顺清楚
Let me get this straight.
你教给烟幕的都是些他无论如何也用不上的快餐知识？
So you taught Smokescreen everything he never needed to know about fast food.
他驾驶考试通过了 寓教于乐
He passed drivers ed. Work hard, play hard.
没错 制作这些照片没让任何人类受伤 不骗你！
Uh, yeah. No humans were harmed in the making of these photos... honest.
你解密了下一个铁堡坐标？
You have decoded the next Iacon coordinates?
非常好 声波
Excellent, Soundwave!
这正是测试我们这个诱饵的大好时机…
Then it is time to beta test our decoy.
我快要解出下一个铁堡坐标了
I am nearly finished decoding the next Iacon coordinates.
你可能没必要继续解了 擎天柱
You may not need to complete your task, Optimus.
铁堡信号？
An Iacon-locator beacon.
看来霸天虎已经挖出了下一个遗物
It seems the Decepticons have already excavated the next relic.
救护车 锁定位置 启动环陆桥
Ratchet, triangulate coordinates and activate the ground bridge.
跟虎子们大干一场！
Bring on the Cons!
烟幕呢？
Where is Smokescreen?
跟杰克在外面“学习”呢
Out training again with Jack.
我们不能等了
We can not wait.
汽车人 变形 出发！
Autobots, transform and roll out!
威震天陛下！
Lord Megatron!
要是我们新出土的文物是霸天虎的
I certainly hope that our new acquisition is of Decepticon origin.
这不可能！
It cannot be.
如此强大的力量
Power of this magnitude
绝对不能落入擎天柱之手
must never be allowed to fall into the hands of Optimus Prime...
绝对不行！
No matter what.
给我…
Come here!
这岩石牢不可破！
The rock is impermeable!
遗物产生了一种保护层！
The relic is emanating a protective shield!
只有领袖之力能唤醒它！
It will only respond to the power of a Prime.
要带走它 我们就得移走整座山！
We will remove it if we have to take the entire mountain!
擎天柱 我又发现了另一个铁堡信号！
Optimus, I just picked up a second Iacon-locator beacon.
擎天柱 听到了吗？
Optimus, do you read?
没虎子的踪影！
No sign of Cons.
哦 老兄 我老板要吓死了！
Oh, dude! My boss is gonna freak!
我们塞到他排气管里那玩意儿
That thing we stuffed in his tailpipe...
叫什么来着？
What's it called again?
披萨！
Pizza!
你们俩能小声点吗？
Will you two keep it down?
阿尔茜？隔板？有谁能听见我说话吗？
Arcee? Bulkhead? Can anyone hear me?
救护车 怎么回事？
Ratchet, what's going on?
探测器发现了另一个铁堡信号
Our sensors detected a second Iacon-locator beacon
但我联系不上擎天柱
but I can't reach Optimus.
我去
I'll go.
就你一个？
Alone?
你还有更好的选择吗？
You have a better option?
好吧！
Fine.
他虽然答应了
He says "fine"...
但看起来他并不想让我只身前往！
but I don't think he really wants me to go alone.
我好像被神子带坏了…
I... just pulled a "Miko".
有个遗物等着我们去拿！
Let's go grab a relic.
哇哦 是一把剑！
Whoa! It's a sword!
那不是普通的剑
Not just any sword.
看起来像是星辰剑！
That looks like the Star Saber
卓天越铸造的神兵利器！
a legendary weapon forged by Solus Prime...
这都是…民间传说
as lore would have it.
传说它能使用领导模块的力量
It's rumored to wield the power of the Matrix.
我要为擎天柱争光
I'm gonna make Optimus proud.
那不是个好主意
Not a good idea.
为什么？
Why?
因为威震天在这里
Because Megatron's here.
黑魔王本尊
The Dark Lord himself.
他不会想到是谁黑了他！
He won't know what hit him.
烟幕 等等 有点不对劲！
Smokescreen, wait. Something isn't right.
为什么威震天没有直接拿走星辰剑？
Why doesn't Megatron just take the Star Saber?
他有洁癖？
Germaphobe?
说真的 我们得等援兵！
Seriously, we need to wait for backup.
你知道救护车怎么说的 现在援兵来不了
You heard Ratchet. Backup's not available right now.
好了！
Enough!
开始运输！
Commence transport!
我的卡隆竞技场啊 那是谁？
Who in the pits of Kaon is that?
见鬼！
Scrap!
插得真紧！
It's really in there tight.
不！不该如此！
No! No, this can't be happening!
救护车 你得让擎天柱来这儿 烟幕去抢遗物了
Ratchet, you gotta get Optimus here now. Smokescreen went for the relic.
叫星辰…
I-it's called the "Star Sab..."
看在塞博特恩的份上 你在哪儿？
Where in the name of Cybertron are you?
还有你是不是提到星辰…？
And did you say "Star Sabe"?
我的天…
Oh, my...
杰克！
Jack!
擎天柱 请回答！
Optimus, please respond!
我知道你们还活着 擎天柱
I can see that you're alive, Optimus.
为什么不回答我？
Why won't you answer me?
噢 每当我们靠近时 信号就移动了！
Every time we get close to the beacon, the signal moves.
走了这么多脚程 我都手痒了
All this legwork is giving me itchy fists!
看来我们被霸天虎给耍了
It seems we have been led astray by a Decepticon trick.
出状况了！
We have a situation.
把他带过来！
Bring him to me.
你叫什么 汽车人？
What is your name, Autobot?
怎么？凭什么告诉你？
Why? Who wants to know?
擎天柱在哪儿？
Where's Optimus?!
别让擎天柱拿到遗物！
Keep Prime from the relic!
有我做你的后盾呢！
I got your back.
阿尔茜！
Arcee!
你到底在想些什么！
What could you possible have been thinking?!
肯定是被我弄松了！
I loosened it for him.
把山扔到他头上！
Drop the mountain on him.
擎天柱 退后！
Optimus, retreat!
快！
Now!
刚才他是不是…？
Did he just...
不可能！
No way.
这都行？
He can do that?
我们霸天虎…迎来了最黑暗的时刻
We Decepticons now face our darkest hour.
那简直帅呆了！
How epic was that!!
我亲视觉电路所见…
I-I saw it with my own optics.
…仍然难以置信
But I still don't believe it.
知道我最难以置信的是什么吗？
You know what I don't believe?
在反复叮嘱你之后
That after everything you've been told
你还是令一个人类陷入了危险
you still put a human at risk.
阿尔茜 那不是他的错 我本该…
A-Arcee, it wasn't his fault. I shouldn't have g...
别逼老娘发作 明天再跟你算帐
Don't you even start with me! We'll talk tomorrow!
送杰克回家！
Send Jack home.
绿灯行…
Green for "go".
我们的队伍需要的是一个成熟的汽车人
We've been in need of another Autobot in our ranks
而不是小屁孩！
not another child.
听着 阿尔茜 我又错了 很抱歉
Look, Arcee, I was wrong, and I'm sorry... again.
要是你想把我赶出领袖卫队…
And if you need to kick me off team Prime...
忽视人类的安全 抑或任何人的安全
Disregard for human safety... or anyone's safety...
都不容原谅 你明白了吗？
will not be tolerated. Do you understand?
完全明白 长官
Fully, sir.
我们决不能忘记 在这个星球上
We must never lose sight of the fact that upon this Earth
我们是巨人 而这种力量 必须谨慎使用
we are titans, and such power must be used wisely.
哇哦！
Whoa!
擎天柱 说句话
Optimus, speak to me!
擎天柱
Optimus!
我收到了一条信息
I am receiving a message.
谁发来的？
From who?
钛师傅…
Alpha Trion.